# Evangelia Tremou, Ph.D.



evangelia.tremou@cea.fr



Website



in Linkedin



#### Scientific Interests

 Radio observations and interferometric techniques are the main tools I use to carry out my research which focuses on the physics of compact objects and radio transients. I am interested in deep radio surveys that allow us to explore the time-variable radio sky (explosions, collisions, disruption events) and constrain the rates and the physical mechanisms that drive these events.

# **Employment History**

2017 - today • Research Associate. CEA-Saclay and Université Paris VII (Paris Diderot), Gif-Sur-Yvette, France

2015 - 2017• Research Associate. Michigan State University MI, USA

2012 - 2014• Research Associate. Yonsei University Observatory, Seoul, S.Korea



### **Education**

2008 - 2011Ph.D Physics, University of Cologne, Germany



Thesis title: Spectroscopic studies on AGNs and High angular resolution in the NIR: The construction of an imaging beam combiner for the LBT

2002 - 2007 B.Sc. Physics, Aristotle University Thessaloniki Thesis title: HII regions detection in Local Group Census



#### Skills

Languages

 Greek (native), English (professional working proficiency), German (elementary proficiency), Korean (beginner).

**Astronomical Tools** 

Virtual Observatory (VO) tools, AIPS, Difmap, CASA, DDFacet, WSClean, AOFlagger, GILDAS, SCHED, IRAF, Starlink, SExtractor, DAOPhot II, SBIG Photometry System, Maxim DL.

**Programming** 

 Python, R language, IDL language for Visualization, Fortran, PHP, HTML, CSS, C-shell, AWK.

Databases

**Graphics & Documents** 

MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite.

MTFX, Microsoft Office, Matplotlib, Mathematica, Matlab.

# **Experience**

- Radio observations and data analysis. Continuum data of MeerKAT, Very Large Array (VLA), Australia Telescope Compact Array (ATCA), Korean VLBI Network (KVN), VERA (VLBI Exploration of Radio Astrometry), IRAM 30m, Effelsberg Radio telescope 100 meters.
- Optical observations and data analysis. Photometry and spectroscopy with Southern Astrophysical Research Telescope (SOAR 4.1m), 1.2m telescope Kryonerion Astronomical Station of the National Observatory of Athens, ESO 1m Schmidt telescope, 24-inch telescope MSU Campus Observatory, 20cm refractor telescope of the University of Thessaloniki and several smaller scopes.
- **Infrared instrumentation**. LINC-NIRVANA Near infrared imaging instrument for the Large Binocular Telescope (see PhD thesis for details).
- **Teaching.** I have taught classes of undergrad level such as: Elements creation and nucleosynthesis, Computational astronomy, Observational astronomy.
- Mentoring. Advisor of undergraduate thesis projects and co-advisor of several master and PhD students.

# **Publications**

Updated publication list at: % NASA ADS

